Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we're going
to be helping you set up an
answering machine basically.
That's right, so
somebody's calling you, you
can't answer the phone
so you leave a message
and we're going to teach
you all about that today.
That's right, so let's take a listen to our
dialogue and we'll be back in a moment
to figure out just what's going on.
Can you help me set up
my voicemail message?
I just got the service and I'm not
really sure what I'm supposed to say.
Sure, you just basically got to let the
caller know who they called and ask them for
their contact information
so you can call them back.
Okay so I can say this
is Abby's voicemail, I will
call you later so leave
me your name a number.
That's more or less the idea but try
something that sounds more friendly.
Okay so how about this?
This is Abby and I'm
really happy you called,
I promise I will give
you a ring as soon
as I can so please leave me your
name a number, talk to you soon.
A little too friendly
Abby, just say this,
hi you've reached Abby,
I'm unable to answer
your call right now
but if you leave me your
name and phone number I will get
back to you as soon as possible, thanks.
That's perfect.
Can you say that again
and record it for me?
All right we're back so now let's
take a look at some language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right in the first sentence
we are asking someone to help
me set up my voicemail message
so we got two key words there.
That's right so let's break it up, the
first one is a phrasal verb to set up, okay.
You can set a lot of things up but just
remember that set and up, these are the two
words that go together,
in this case we're setting up
voicemail, it means to establish
or to start or to put together.
Yeah to install, like
for example you get a
new computer and you
have to connect all the
cables and you have to
connect the monitor so
you said can you help
me set up my computer?
That's right so he always helps me
set it up so my computer for example.
That's right and what
we're setting up is our
voicemail message so
what exactly is voicemail?
So you know what mail
is, we have email and
regular mail, voicemail
is the kind of message
you receive on your
phone, your cell phone
or your home phone when
you don't answer the phone.
That's right so basically
a way for people
to leave you a message even
though you can't answer them.
That's right so this
is something that's,
it's not text, it's
actually a voice, that's
why it's called voice mail and you have
to set it up, okay so there's no automatic
voicemail message you
actually have to make your own
or you can choose one and
today we're making our own.
That's right and so
we're explaining that we
actually just got this
service and we don't
really know what we're supposed
to say or how to set up our voicemail.
That's right so voicemail
messages are kind
of service and now who would
offer this kind of service Marco?
Probably your telephone company.
That's right so a telephone
company will offer
many different services
and these are things
that you can pay extra
for and they're useful
they can help you in
some way so another
kind of service is
three-way calling, that's
right so actually we're
taking a look at this
word service as a noun so we
have a service or this service.
So the company offers this service and well
why are we setting up the voicemail and our
friend explains that
we just basically doing
it to let the collar
know who they called.
Okay so if I call a
number and it says hey
leave a message, I don't
know who I'm leaving
a message for did I
dial the wrong number?
What do I say?
Do I say my phone number?
So this is basically
instructions for what to say?
That's right and you
become the collar, that's right.
So whoever is making
the call is called the
collar and this is why
we are setting up our
voicemail to let the collar
know who we are calling and of
course we have to ask the collar
for their contact information.
All right now this is
important because it's
not just something you
have with voicemail messages.
You have contact information
from many different things.
For example your medical care, your school
you have to include contact information.
Now this would be your phone
number, your address and/or your email.
That's right.
So your contact
information is not only useful
for in a voicemail message but for example
in a business meeting or a business lunch
you want to get maybe someone else's contact
information so you can call them later.
That's right.
So don't forget it's
all see your name as
well so I forgot to
mention that that's right.
Your contact information
must have your name.
All right so that's pretty much all we have
for the first part of language takeaway.
Why don't we listen to
the dialogue again and
we'll be back in a bit
with fluency builder.
Can you help me set up
my voicemail message?
I just got the service and I'm not
really sure what I'm supposed to say.
Sure you just basically
got to let the collar
know who they called
and ask them for their
contact information so
you can call them back.
Okay so I can say this is Abby's voicemail.
I will call you later so leave
me your name a number.
That's more or less the idea but try
something that sounds more friendly.
Okay so how about this?
This is Abby and I'm
really happy you called.
I promise I will give
you a ring as soon as
I can so please leave
me your name a number.
Talk to you soon.
A little too friendly Abby.
Just say this.
Hi you've reached Abby.
I'm unable to answer
your call right now but
if you leave me your
name and phone number
I will get back to you
as soon as possible.
Thanks.
That's perfect.
Can you say that again
and record it for me?
All right here we are
in fluency builder and
the first phrase we've
got is how about this?
So we're saying we're saying
we've got an example for you.
How about this?
That's right.
Then the example.
So we've talked about how about many times
already so for example you know how about
we go to the movies
or how not to say how
about your weekend because
that's completely wrong.
In this occasion we're
talking about how
about this and this is like
setting it up for an example.
That's right so for
another example we could
say so Marco I'm
trying to figure out how
to say hello when I answer the phone
because I don't like the way I say it now.
It's like say how about this?
Hello?
That's right.
Hello.
That's too strong.
Yeah that's good.
All right so basically I'm
setting up an example.
We're saying okay keep
listening I will give you an example.
Yeah just imagine that
you're trying on different
clothes and someone is
giving you their opinion.
So maybe you try on a black shirt
and you say how about this one?
Yeah boring.
And then you try on a green one
and you say now how about this better.
So then you're giving
them other options and
examples and this is
why we say how about
this and then we give
the example like Abby did.
And you're also asking for a
response you're asking for an opinion.
And so what Abby's saying is I promise
I will give you a ring as soon as I can.
Now this phrase give
you a ring is very British
English but it's also
something you should
know if you want to be in America
because you'll hear it in TV and stuff.
That's right it's actually
a colloquial term
for saying I will call
you I will call you
I will call you back
or I will give you a call.
So the telephone rings that's the verb
that goes with a phone right ring ring.
So I will give you a ring means I will
call you just like you just said Markham.
That's right.
So remember this
phrase it's actually it
may seem a little bit
confusing but remember
it has to do with
calling someone I will
give you a ring is I will call you or if
you say hey give me a ring later on this
afternoon it's call me
later this afternoon.
All right and then
moving towards the end of
the dialogue Abby says
hi you have reached Abby.
Okay this is weird because she is Abby
but she's saying you have reached Abby.
Right you're speaking about
yourself in the third person.
That's right so this is a message
so you're telling people what to do.
Like I said they're
instructions and so this
is basically the first
thing you say you have
reached Catherine that means the number
you dialed is Catherine's phone number.
So you reached that
means that you've contacted.
Right exactly so as
you say it's important if
you ever call a bank
or any type of company
it will say you have
reached Wells Fargo bank
something and it will
tell you what number
you call because maybe
you put in your finger
wrong and you just
called the wrong number.
That's right or you could
use the word reached
in a different way
for example yesterday
I was very angry at
Marco because I couldn't
reach him by phone I
called and called and
called and couldn't reach him and
I realized then his phone is broken.
That's right so actually this verb to reach
someone also has to do with with in general
with calling I was trying to reach you all
afternoon but I couldn't get a hold of you.
That's right and I
was so frustrated well
actually if I had
voicemail I would continue
by saying I am unable
to answer your call
right now because maybe
my phone is off maybe
I am busy so we say I am unable
to answer your call right now.
Alright now this seems really long okay and
a little bit strange but this is basically
the standard for how to record a message I
am unable to answer your call right now so
you answer the phone right or you answer
a phone call but in this case I am unable
to that means I can't
talk to you for whatever
reason I am out of the house I am busy so
I am unable to answer your call right now
just remember that that means I can't talk
to you right now I can't be on the phone.
And actually this word
unable sounds a lot
more polite and a lot more
formal than saying I can't.
That's right and
that's why we use it on
messages like this because
it is so polite and so nice.
Alright so that's all the
time we have for Fluency
Builder let's take a listen to
our dialogue one last time.
Can you help me set up
my voicemail message?
I just got the service and I am not
really sure what I am supposed to say.
Sure you just basically
got to let the caller
know who they called
and ask them for the
contact information so
you can call them back.
Okay so I can say this
is Abby's voicemail I will
call you later so leave
me your name a number.
That's more or less the idea but try
something that sounds more friendly.
Okay so how about this?
This is Abby and I am
really happy you called.
I promise I will give
you a ring as soon as
I can so please leave
me your name a number.